VALERIO INNOCENTI SEDILI

+393311202861 - vinnocenti@outlook.it - Bologna (Italy), viale Gaetano Salvemini 11/10



Hi, my name is Valerio, and I am a programmer. I like writing code, experimenting with innovative approaches, learning and doing research. I am passionate and curious about news in the developer community and I like to thoroughly understand the tools I am using. I work as a front-end web developer in Abstract. I studied physics and learned on the field in many technological fields. In my free time, I am an active volunteer in scouting and in the local developer communities.

WFB DEVELOPMENT

React, Typescript, GraphQL,, HTML, Javascript (ESNext)
CSS, Sass, CSS in JS
Node, Webpack, Express, MongoDB REST API
C# ASP.NET, Wordpress plugin and theme development
CICD (Gitlab, Jenkins), Docker, CICD, Git
Network and cloud (AWS, Azure, Digital Ocean)
W3C standard and Web Content Accessibility Guidelines

OTHER PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Agile and Scrum development experience
Experience in project and people management
Critical and proactive thinker
Comfortable with being the 'go to' person in a company
Focus on performance budget and mobile development
Machine Learning and scientific programming
Design, UX (Photoshop, Illustrator) and 3d graphics

EMPLOYMENT

2019 - present

FRONTEND DEVELOPER - Abstract S.r.l.

Maintenance and development for Smartshopper Web Application, internal tools,

- + Headless Node.js application using Express and MongoDB.
- + Static Website using React and GatsbyJS

2016 - 2019

FRONTEND DEVELOPER - Yoox Net a Porter - Modis

Maintenance and development for www.kartell.com inside a team using Agile and Scrum methodologies

- + ASP.NET MVC development using internal Framework
- + Wordpress theme and store locator development
- + Legacy code and Accessibility refactoring
- + Node.js and Selenium library development for e2e browser testing (main maintainer)
- + Jenkins library development using Docker on Linux and Windows (lead developer)
- + React PWA poc for school coaching (speaker and lead developer)

2014 - 2015

HIL TEST DEVELOPER - Intern at Magneti Marelli

- + Software development for HILs applications
- + Python control library development
- + Matlab Simulink model testing and validation

2011 INFORMATION RETRIEVAL - in Cervetti Project using python

2008 IT TECH SUPPORT – in Arpa Emilia Romagna

EDUCATION

2016

	 + ASP.NET MVC programming + ADO.NET Entity Framework and SQL + HTML, CSS, JS development
2016	 EMBEDDED SOFTWARE DEVELOPER - Futura + Arduino and Raspberry Pi development + Linux bash scripting and C Library Development + STM32F4 ARM Cortex programming + Networking, I2C and CAN bus + HTML, CSS, JS development
2009 - 2015	 PHYSICS BACHELOR'S DEGREE - Not Achieved - University of Bologna + Thesis: Validation of a Diesel engine model for hardware in the loop simulations + C++ MPI Cluster programming for scientific computing + C++ QT genetic algorithm machine learning bot
2015	MACHINE LEARING COURSE - Coursera
2011	PARALLEL OPENMP PROGRAMMING - CINECA
2009	NUCLEAR PHYSICS RESEARCH – summer internship at INFN-LNF
	PROJECTS
2018	OPEN SOURCE CONTRIBUTION
	Zeit SWR, Cucumber JS, Object fit polyfill, Bologna JS website and tools, Docker frontend tools
2017 - 2018	IOT GARBAGE COLLECTION MONITOR Node-RED and Mapbox API
2015	WORDPRESS PLUGINS DEVELOPMENT bolognacngei.it
2013	ARCHEOLOGICAL SITE VISUALIZATION 3D reconstruction using unity

JUNIOR INTERFACE DEVELOPER - OverNet Education

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

2008 - present

SCOUT LEADER - CNGE

- + Cub scouts leader
- + Rover scouts leader
- + World Scouting's Wood Badge

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

I like to go outdoors to disconnect: running, biking, camping and hiking (I should find more time for these activities as I am a little fat). I enjoy computer games, sci-fi movies, TV series and books, tabletop games and RPGs. Really passionate about science, astronomy and technology in general.